Contact

081573550017 (Mobile) zainalrtf@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/zainalsalamun-660a9598 (LinkedIn) www.linkedin.com/redir/generalmalware-page (Blog)

Top Skills

Product Development
Model-view-viewmodel (MVVM)
Product Management

Languages

Bahasa Inggris (Elementary)

Certifications

Dart & Flutter Development Bootcamp: Find House App

Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Flutter untuk Pemula

Memulai Pemrograman Dengan Dart

CCNA

Belajar Membuat Aplikasi Android untuk Pemula

zainal salamun

Android & Flutter Developer | Product Management

West Jakarta, Jakarta, Indonesia

Summary

Experienced as Android Developer with over than 7 year of experience in IT Consultant Company. Strong in Object-Oriented Programming and problem-solving skills. Enthusiastic in implementing SOLID principles which can make the process of developing and maintaining code more efficient and reduces boilerplate codes. Have capability either develops android app from scratch or re-design architecture to be more maintainable and scalable.

Experience

Jutive

Flutter Developer

November 2023 - Present (3 months)

Singapura, Singapura

Designing and creating applications using the Futter platform and collaborating with the UI UX team and the backend developer team, making innovations by making products that clients like.

improve application performance and implement new technologies to maximize development, and maintain code quality.

Binar Academy

2 years 10 months

Mobile Developer

April 2021 - Present (2 years 10 months)

Jakarta Raya, Indonesia

Designing and creating applications using the Futter platform and collaborating with the UI UX team and the backend developer team, making innovations by making products that clients like.

Bug fixes and improve application performance and implement new technologies to maximize development, and maintain code quality. Project Coverage:

Client: Product Yokke!

Project name: Yokke Biz Lite (Point Of Sale)

Position in Project : Flutter Developer

Responsibility : Development Mobile Application

Technology: Dart, flutter, MVVM, Dio, State Management GetX, OTP

Database : Oracle

- Daily Works:

Work as flutter developer team.

Continuously maintains and improves code to reduces boilerplate codes

Bug Resolution.

improve performance

Write code in DART flutter framework

Implement New/Change Request.

Implement GetX State Management

Implement Dio package

Redesign product

Flutter MVVM

API Integration

Payment Transfer bank integration

Qris payment integration

Developing follow design figma UI UX

Testing

Build and Compile

Project Coverage:

Client: BANK OCBC

Project name: Nyala Bisnis Merchant (OCBC QRIS)

Position in Project : Flutter Developer

Responsibility : Development Mobile Application

Technology: Dart, flutter, MVVM, Dio, State Management GetX, Firebase,

OneSignal, OTP

Database : Oracle

- Daily Works:

Work as flutter developer team.

Continuously maintains and improves code to reduces boilerplate codes

Bug Resolution.

improve performance

Write code in DART flutter framework

Implement New/Change Request.

Implement GetX State Management

Implement Dio package

Implement OneSignal Notification

Redesign product

Flutter MVVM

API Integration

Integration MAAS system

Qris payment integration PTEN

Developing follow design figma UI UX

Testing SIT UAT

Testing release Testflight and firebase distribution

Build and Compile

Student Product Management

October 2022 - March 2023 (6 months)

Jakarta Raya, Indonesia

- Research, analyze, define product features
- Creating User persona, Customer Journey mapping
- Determine the OKR matric hypothesis
- Create a product MVP
- Creating Product Required Document (PRD), wireframes and workflows.

Collaborate with Team UIUX

- Final project revamp app flash coffe

Buana Varia Komputama

Android Developer

November 2016 - April 2021 (4 years 6 months)

JI. Pakubuwono VI No.24, RT.9/RW.6, Gunung, Kby. Baru, Kota Jakarta Selatan, DKI

Design and build advanced applications for the Android platform

Collaborate with cross-functional teams to define, design, and ship new

features

Work with outside data sources and APIs

Unit-test code for robustness, including edge cases, usability, and general reliability

Work on bug fixing and improving application performance

Continuously discover, evaluate, and implement new technologies to maximize development efficiency and help maintain code quality, organization, and automatization

Work as a single android developer.

Deploy Development, Staging, and Production Environment

Continuously maintains and improves code to reduce boilerplate codes

Education

Universitas Teknologi Digital Indonesia Gelar Sarjana, Informatika · (2012 - 2016)